Let's go. I'll show you the $mol framework.
It's a web framework which
gives you one app for Web, Windows, macOS,
Linux, Android, iOS, Web Extension if you use Tauri.
Also, you can use your app like PWA,
a TV application, because it works offline. No internet needed.
Also, your data syncs automatically when online
and with zero conflicts by CRDT types.
You need no server, no database, no backups.
All data is safe on clients.
Auth happens instantly on first page load.
You have local state and your data
syncs via Giper Baza.
Also, you have strong types, real-time sync,
end-to-end encryption by default.
It helps you create websites that behave
like a native app with zero server infrastructure.
Let's start.
We have our place. Okay. Let's install.
And start it.
Let's go to localhost.
And we have many namespaces. For example,
my namespace "bog". And I can show some of
my app. And it gets cloned automatically.
It uses a package "fema". And this package
was also cloned automatically.
Okay, this same app.
Let's go back.
Let's create our own namespace.
It will be called "my namespace".
Next, we need to replace "company_template"
with our namespace and project name.
Let's do this.
My namespace. And it will be called "my_app".
Next, we need to replace "company/template"
with our path.
We need to change the name
to "my_app". Because $mol uses snake_case.
And namespace is also the folder path.
my_namespace/my_app/app.
And the file app.view.tree -
it's declarative syntax for HTML.
Okay, let's see.
We need... my namespace. Yeah.
Okay. My app. App. Yeah, it works. Cool.
Also, see docs.
Yeah, we see docs. Okay, very cool.
Now we can save this and
publish on GitHub Pages.
Okay, we need to create a repository.
Maybe "my_space_my_app". Initing it.
In MAM we have other options. We can have
one big repository. Like $mol - one repository
for all modules, apps, and classes.
But I have a namespace with multiple repositories.
And I have many applications.
Also, we need GitHub workflows.
Rich template already exists. Git commit...
Git commit "init". Okay. Cool.
Let's make the repository.
This repository must be called the same as
your app. Because when you clone it,
the folder must have the same name.
"my_app". Okay.
You can also call it another name,
but you will need to rename it when you clone your application.
Yeah, we need to remove origin
and add new origin. Okay.
Now we have the application and our action
started to build our app.
Okay. While it's building, we can change
our GitHub Pages settings.
This action creates a branch "gh-pages"
and we add this as a branch deployment.
Okay, we're done. It was one minute.
We need to deploy from branch "gh-pages". Save.
Okay, cool.
We have a second workflow. That was the first time.
Next time we just need to push to master.
It's done.
We need to add our URL here.
And yeah, we have our application here. Nice.
Also, you can add your CNAME.
Next, I want to tell you how to create
a web application. We can create a module
without index.html. But when we add index.html,
we create a web application.
And this body with $mol_root...
it's a simple single-page application.
And here we add our script web.js.
Next, I want to build for production,
like on GitHub. For this, I use "npm start" and
the path: my_namespace/my_app/app.
Because we build the app.
Now we see index.html here.
Manifest JSON by default for PWA.
Web.js. And CSS in JSON.
Okay, let me see this.
Yeah, here's our application. Okay.
I need to explain how to change HTML here.
It's simple because view.tree is declarative
syntax for creating HTML.
The base class is $mol_view.
$mol_view can be any HTML element.
For example, here I change "hello" to just some div.
And in HTML we have a human-readable path
to our content: my_app_app.Root.Div.
And now we can easily style it
in app.view.css.ts.
app.view.css.ts. We need to use
$mol_style_define. And here we can
write styles for our application.
We have Root,
in Root we have child zero, and we have Div.
Okay. Let's go. Color.
Make color red for this text.
Okay, we have Div. And here, color... red.
Yeah. Cool.
And deploy to production.
You can use any object. In any object
you can add in $mol_view
any method, any new method.
And you can replace any method.
For example, I can replace plugins
in my $mol_view Div and use my own "fema".
Two minutes and we have our changes on production.
Nice.
I added some logic to our application.
I created app.view.ts and wrote some logic.
Cool. To summarize: app.view.tree for HTML.
And we have our TypeScript classes here.
We can change any methods or add new ones in view.ts.
Or add logic. And we have styles
in view.css.ts. Typed.
Here I see an error file.
File errors, we have here.
And it helps us understand what error we have.
Okay, I fixed it with the help of an LLM.
We just need to add null
here because it's events.
And we need default values. Okay.
For LLM, I created a skill and you can add it
by this command. I'll leave it in the description.
Also, $mol supports GLSL format for shaders.
Next, I want to show the localization feature.
You can add the @ symbol for any text.
And it will be localized automatically.
For any language, you can just add
a locale file for our component.
And in JSON, you have the localization.
Also, I created a second page - Giper Baza.
Now we have our ID. We are already registered by default.
Because we load the application once.
Okay, also we have adaptation.
And... thank you.